<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentations on Openness &amp; Sensitivity: Practical Concerns In Taking Archaeological Data Online</title>
    <link>/categories/presentations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentations on Openness &amp; Sensitivity: Practical Concerns In Taking Archaeological Data Online</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/presentations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data, Indigenous Knowledge, and Archaeology: The need for community-driven open data projects</title>
      <link>/open-data-supernant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/open-data-supernant/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Kisha Supernant Department of Anthropology, University of Alberta
DRAFT: Do not cite in any context without the permission of the author
Introduction: With the rise of the digital age, new possibilities for expanding the accessibility and long-term sustainability of archaeological data have emerged. A body of literature over the past ten years has contributed to important debates about the role of digitization of, open access to, and community engagement with both digitized and born-digital archaeological data (Beale 2012; Beck and Neylon 2012; Bevan 2012; Costa, et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Should Reassess How We Define Sensitive Archaeological Data and How We Share It</title>
      <link>/reassess-vawser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reassess-vawser/</guid>
      <description>Anne M. Wolley Vawser Midwest Archeological Center National Park Service Think back to your first field school when you learned the basics of archeological investigations, whether it was excavating a roman ruin or conducting pedestrian survey in some western US state. Your professors and TAs were always after you to document, document, document through field notes and forms, and maybe later you were lucky enough to help write up part of the report of your findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinterpreting state shifts using legacy data: colonialism and zooarchaeological assemblages in southern Arizona</title>
      <link>/legacy-mathwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/legacy-mathwich/</guid>
      <description>Nicole Mathwich, Ph.D. Arizona State Museum, University of Arizona, Tuscon, AZ ABSTRACT
Complex systems approaches to archaeological interpretation are well-established in the discipline and offer important ways for studying change over various scales. Large datasets and regional syntheses invite new applications of complex systems applications of complex systems to archaeological data. At the same time, indigenous and postcolonial perspectives have increasingly become foundational to project planning, data collection, and interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>