<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abstracts on Openness &amp; Sensitivity: Practical Concerns In Taking Archaeological Data Online</title>
    <link>/categories/abstracts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abstracts on Openness &amp; Sensitivity: Practical Concerns In Taking Archaeological Data Online</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/abstracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract: How do we keep “bro-ing” away from open access archaeology?: Open Access, Cultural Appropriation, and Archaeology</title>
      <link>/abstract-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstract-white/</guid>
      <description>William A. White, III Assistant Professor
Department of Anthropology
University of California, Berkeley
Abstract “Bro-ing” is a market research practice pioneered by Nike and reported by Naomi Klein (2000:75) where designers bring prototypes to inner-city neighborhoods to gauge reactions to new styles and products. This practice also creates buzz that can be used to sell those products to the same communities.
Open access archaeology helps make archaeological data available to larger research communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract: Chacoan Complexities</title>
      <link>/abstract-martin-heitman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstract-martin-heitman/</guid>
      <description>The Chaco Research Archive (CRA, chacoarchive.org) has been available since 2004 and the Salmon Pueblo Archaeological Research Collection (SPARC, salmonpueblo.org) launched in May of 2018. These web-based portals, as their names indicate, were both designed primarily with the academic researcher in mind. While these resources acknowledge the diverse descendant communities within the Southwest, neither has deliberately focused on eliciting robust Native perspectives to coincide with Euro-American forms of archaeological classification and interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract: Respecting the Past and Protecting the Future: Strategies for Implementing Digital Best Practices in Historical Archaeology Research on Military Installations</title>
      <link>/abstract-noack-myers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abstract-noack-myers/</guid>
      <description>In Cultural Resources Management, many archaeological survey projects are undertaken through contract services provided to regional federal clients with large-scale resource evaluation needs. In the case of military properties, each installation maintains SOPs and curatorial operations to serve the needs of their unique CRM department. While modern military and government security may exist at the forefront of on-the-ground practice at these locations, the historical research and archaeological data related to historic and precolonial communities and individuals that once resided on these properties should be handled with equal sensitivity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>